dfds.co.uk 2019-10-26

# Our Privacy Policy - How we Process your Data | DFDS

We collect personal data about you whenever you book with us, travel with us, when you use our websites, or when you use our call centres. We also collect personal data when you book our freight or logistics services.​

In case you booked by telephone, we have due to the need of documentation a call record in some countries that we are holding for up to one year.​

## Payments online

When you pay online, you will be transferred to a secure webpage where you will add your payment card details. ​

All payments are processed by our trusted partner's platform and validated against the highest standards of securing and safeguarding of card data. We do not process or store any payment card information in DFDS. However, in case you have questions about the processing of your payment card details, please contact DFDS, and we will reach out to our payment partner. 

## Personal profile 

Your personal data is also used if you have created a profile on one of DFDS' websites. If you have created a profile with DFDS and given your consent, we will register your purchase to help us administer your profile, and use this information to target you with offers and products. The information is also used to recognise you when you book with us (assuming you are logged in) and to follow up on reservations. The information is also used for contests and statistics.​

## How do we protect your personal data?

When you book with us, we use secure server software, which encrypts all of the information you enter before it is sent to us. This encryption ensures that the information is appropriately protected against unauthorised interception.​

## How long do we keep your personal data? 

The personal data in the booking information will be kept for a period corresponding to the time where we can be met with claims. 

If you register a personal profile or subscribe to the e-mail service, we will store your personal data until you delete the profile or unsubscribe from our newsletter. The information will make future bookings easier, as we have already saved your personal data.

To be sure we have updated information about our customers, we will encourage you to make necessary changes in your profile. If your profile has not been used or activated for 3 years, we will delete it.​

## Subscription to the e-mail service and contests

When we offer you a subscription to our e-mail and marketing services, we will ask for your name and e-mail address so that we can send you our e-mail newsletter. Your name is not required to subscribe to our e-mail service, and you will be able to opt out at any time by clicking the unsubscribe link in the newsletter. When you enter a contest or take advantage of other promotional offers, we may ask for your name, address and e-mail address so we can administer contests and notify the winners. ​

## Our use of cookies 

DFDS uses cookies on its websites and the booking system to ensure consistency throughout the reservation process. 

Cookies are small pieces of information that are stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive. For further information visit: <https://www.dfds.com/en-gb/legal/cookies>. ​

## Mobile Applications

DFDS maintains several mobile applications (apps) to enhance our customer's experiences. The same principles detailed in this privacy policy apply for those who use our apps. We utilise anonymous tracking software, namely Google Analytics and Firebase, to measure the usage of our apps, and we only collect personal data to the extent required for the actual functions of that particular app (such as your location in the world at a given time). Any and all data collected about you through our apps is used only by DFDS, and is not shared with any third party, other than the programs named above.

## Will DFDS disclose the data to third parties? 

Personal data will be shared internally within DFDS' organisation, as we have the same booking system. We have internal policies and agreements in place to ensure an adequate level of protection irrespective of where in DFDS your data is located. 

We will not transfer personally identifiable information about our visitors or customers to a third party, except in the following cases:

  * Service providers and advisors that we use to provide certain services, such as hotels and activity providers. In such case, the suppliers will be individual data controllers;
  * If we are legally required to do so;
  * DFDS may provide aggregate statistics about our customers, sales, traffic patterns, loyalty card memberships and related site information to third-party partners.
  * In addition, DFDS may provide information about our customers to third parties who provide services or functions on our behalf, including payment card processing, business analytics, customer service, marketing, or distribution of surveys. 
  * We may also authorise third parties to collect information on our behalf, including if necessary to operate features of our website or to facilitate the delivery of online advertising tailored to your interests.
  * We may share your details with a third party who may actively follow up on incomplete bookings via email.
  * Your email address may be shared with Facebook for social media marketing campaigns.
  * In the event we sell property or safety of DFDS, its employees and others, or in the event we sell or liquidate any part of business or assets;

Any such sharing will be in compliance with data protection law, and only to trustworthy third parties.

We always strive to clearly inform you regarding the uses and possible disclosure of your information when such information is obtained. If it is not practical to do so at the point of collection, we will inform you as soon as possible, unless there is a legitimate basis for not doing so. For example, where it is necessary for the prevention or detection of a crime or where otherwise permitted by law. 

## Security and safety onboard

Following a thorough investigation, the names of undesirable passengers can be placed on an internal list to prevent these passengers from booking and travelling with us if the master of the vessel has reason to believe that the passengers will pose a security risk and in accordance with the terms and conditions applicable for the travel. Passengers are deemed to pose a security risk if they have endangered the safety of themselves, the vessel, the crew or other passengers, if their behaviour has been inappropriate during a previous trip or if they have failed to follow safety regulations or requirements. DFDS will register the necessary personal information of the banned passengers. This will prevent those passengers deemed a security risk from booking trips on our passenger ships for a defined period. The information will not be held for longer than necessary.​

## Your permission

In using the DFDS website, you consent to the collection and use of this information by DFDS in the methods described above. If our Privacy Policy should change, we will make the relevant changes here so that you are always aware of the information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances it might be disclosed. ​

## Do you want more information about your data?

You are always welcome to contact us regarding the data we have registered and request a description of the personal information we have collected and processed and the types of recipients – to whom DFDS will, or may, disclose that information. 

You are also welcome to contact us if you would like us to correct, erase or block inaccurate information. DFDS always attempts to respond to valid requests as quickly as possible.

We kindly ask you to send any requests or questions to [privacy@dfds.com](mailto:privacy@dfds.com "DFDS Privacy Email")

If you have signed up to receive our e-mail newsletter you can always unsubscribe via the link in the newsletter or by contacting DFDS on the above email address.​

## Data controller:

 **DFDS A/S**

Address: Sundkrogsgade 11, DK-2100 Copenhagen, Denmark

Reg.nr.:

Tel.: +45 33 42 33 42​

## Who to contact

If you have any questions about this privacy policy, or you want to obtain insight into personal data held about you, you may contact us via [privacy@dfds.com](mailto:privacy@dfds.com "DFDS Privacy Email")​

If you prefer to contact your local call centre, you shall be more than welcome to do so. They will then assist you with your questions.

## If you have a complaint

If you want to lodge a complaint, we refer you to Datatilsynet, Borgergade 28 (5), 1300 København K, Denmark.  ​

 ​​​​​
